ELLEN HSU

Business Data Analyst

www.linkedin.com/in/ellenyhsu

503-313-3388 ellemonke@gmail.com

Ambitious and MBA-educated Data Analyst with a capacity for learning and producing at a fast pace. Knowledgeable about business, sales, retail and marketing. Experienced at frontend web development and design, turning complex and messy problems into nice digestible end-products. Passionate about helping people achieve their goals and bridging the communication gap between technicians and consumers.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Full Stack Programming: Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Data Analytics & Visualizations: Matplotlib, D3, Leaflet, Tableau, Excel VBA
- **E-Commerce & Marketing:** more than 15 years prior experience in digital marketing.
- **Project Management:** for corporate and small business websites, digital asset systems.
- Creative & Entrepreneurial: striving for big goals and achieving quantifiable results.

PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

- Global Analysis: https://ellemonke.github.io/COVID-19/
 Designed a unique perspective and visualizations about the current crisis.
 (Python, Pandas, Matplotlib, Web APIs, JavaScript, Leaflet, D3, HTML, CSS).
- Full Stack Development: https://ellemonke.github.io/full-stack-project/ Built a unique correlogram and a responsive website. (Python, JavaScript, Bootstrap).
- Machine Learning: https://predict-hdi.herokuapp.com/ Calculated a predictive model, built an app and a Flask website. (Python, Scikit-learn).
- Data Analysis: https://ellemonke.github.io/eco-analysis/presentation.html
 Developed the story and color design, charted land usage. (Python, Pandas, Matplotlib).
- **E-Commerce:** https://www.vintalier.com/
 Designed the layout, UX, and add-ons; integrated into Google Shopping and Facebook.

EXPERIENCE

Owner, Entrepreneur Vintalier LLC

Portland, OR

02/2009 - 02/2020

- Founded and grew a successful multi-channel retail store, initially e-commerce then as a brick-and-mortar in 2013 and moved Downtown in 2017 to a 1200 sqft space.
- Designed online and financial KPIs to forecast the purchasing of ~\$40K of product each season, analyze sell-through, determine cash flow, and identify market trends.
- Sold on four e-commerce platforms and regularly implemented new e-commerce plugins, social media integration, shipping optimization, and analytics.
- Determined the strategic and creative direction for the brand, executed multi-channel marketing strategies. Managed part-time staff.

Marketing Manager Motech Industries Inc.

Tainan, Taiwan & Newark, DE

07/2009 - 11/2010

- Overhauled the corporate website to a content management system (SharePoint) and trained 30 stakeholders from 7 business groups across 4 languages to be self-sustaining.
- Managed an international marketing budget of ~\$100K and reduced costs ~\$42K.
- Launched a new technical product line and >\$20M worth of new product sold out.
- Drove the strategic and creative direction of quarterly advertising campaigns.
- Worked closely with C-level executives and marketing agencies to lead a re-brand.

Freelance Digital Producer

Portland, OR

06/2008 - 06/2009

ID Branding & Exprima

- Managed feature enhancements for Intel's internal digital asset management system.
- Project managed new websites for small businesses in an agency environment.

Digital Producer Nike (Contract)

Beaverton, OR

11/2006 - 03/2008

- Cleaned 48% of the intranet in obsolete sites; defined account management procedures and implemented chargebacks; recouped an estimated \$340K in annual costs.
- Served as interim Senior Digital Manager; facilitated progress during leadership and IT transitions, functional changes, server and software upgrades, and an intranet refresh.
- Managed 250+ internal accounts and trained clients about new self-publishing tools.

Web Content Developer Intel (Contract)

Hillsboro, OR

11/2005 - 11/2006

- Contributed to the rollout of Intel re-branding while launching product sites monthly.
- Designed live site mockups by popular request and localized content.

Senior Technical Web Writer San Diego Supercomputer Center

La Jolla, CA

04/2004 - 07/2005

- Architected and transitioned a 400-page, cross-departmental website to an upgraded server. Reduced storage consumption by over 40%.
- Developed an extensive survey to define the mission and objectives of user services.
- Collaborated with engineers to write documentation on supercomputing technology.

Web Developer/Designer

San Diego, CA

10/2002 - 04/2004

Virtual Reality Medical Center

- Successfully launched an e-commerce project from conception to completion.
- Monitored Overture and AdWords to improve search engine optimization and statistics.

EDUCATION

- Certificate, Data Analytics, A+ University of Oregon Boot Camp
- MBA, Marketing Marylhurst University
- Certificate, Apparel Entrepreneur Portland Fashion Institute
- BA, Computing and the Arts University of California, San Diego